Argentina, Tucuman

FABIO RAMOS

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

NicLen17

in <u>Fabio Ramos</u> Portfolio <u>fabioramosnic@gmail.com</u> <u>54+ 3813379225</u>

FrontEnd developer with solid knowledge in React, Javascript, Typescript, ECS6+, HTML5 and CSS3, I have 4 years of experience in the programming sector, I specialize in creating accessible, interactive and intuitive interfaces with great attention to detail. Although my main focus is FrontEnd, I also have experience in Full Stack and BackEnd roles, which qualifies me for positions with these characteristics.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

CENSYS S.A. Dec. 2023 - Actualidad

I participated in the development, implementation and maintenance of functional requirements for banking systems, with a Full Stack approach that integrates PowerBuilder in the FrontEnd and SQL in the BackEnd, within an agile framework under the Scrum methodology. I developed modules individually and in groups, I gained experience in the use of technical documentation (AFR and Development Guides). In addition, I provided training to lower senior colleagues, the client and other scrum teams on requirements I developed and technical queries. Manage my work and activities with Jira.

SQL - T-SQL - PowerBuilder - Sybase - Jira - Redmine - Scrum

Full Stack Developer [MERN]

Freelance Jun. 2021 - May. 2024

I carried out the development and maintenance of more than 12 web applications using the MERN stack, including e-commerce, SPAs, blogs, among others. In each application, I ensured performance, responsive design, accessibility, SEO. I deployed all the applications using services such as Vercel, Render and Heroku. I implemented features such as payment gateways and means of contact consuming various APIs (MercadoPago, Nodemailer, WhatsApp, etc.). Additionally, I managed application version control with Git/GitHub and managed the flow of activities using Trello.

React - Node - Javascript/Typescript - HTML5 - CSS - Express - MongoDB - Postman - Git/Github - Trello - SEO **Vercel - Render - Canva**

SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork Troubleshooting
- Attention to detail

- Communication
- Critical thinking
- Versatility

Fast learning

LANGUAGES

- English Advanced B2/C1
- Spanish Native

EDUCATION

Leadership

Information systems engineering

Universidad tecnológica nacional UTN | 2022 - Act

Front-End Developer - Web UI (SSR)

Globant | Jul. 2024 - Oct. 2024

Intensive V - B2 English Certification

IRUSH Institute | Mar. 2024 - Nov. 2024

CERTIFICATIONS

English Studies Certificate - B2

Instituto Rush | 2024

Back-End Node Developer Certificate

RollingCode School | 2024

Official EF SET Certificate - C1 Advanced

EF SET | 2023

QC/QA Testing Certification

Global Learning | 2023

Front-End Programmer Certificated

ITMaster Academy | 2022

Full Stack Web Developer MERN Certificate

RollingCode School | 2021